<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trib0r3&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on trib0r3&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 12:01:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ida Pro Plugins</title>
      <link>/posts/ida-pro-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 12:01:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ida-pro-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plugins worth installing&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expose Any Port With Ngrok</title>
      <link>/posts/expose-any-port-with-ngrok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 13:53:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/expose-any-port-with-ngrok/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to expose any port to the Internet without exposing your private IP (for free).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmap PE Manually</title>
      <link>/posts/unmap-pe-manually/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/unmap-pe-manually/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisities  Make sure that you have dumped binary from memory (optionally) Fix PE headers if necessary  Unmap With PE bear  Open PE-bear &amp;gt; Sections &amp;gt; Section Headers Make sure that VA and VS matches RA and RS, so:  RA[i] = VA[i] RS[i] = RA[i+1] - RA[i] RS.reloc = 0 VS[i] = RS[i]   If you see some red blocks it means that PE is probably misalligned, check: Fix misalligned sections  Fix misalligned sections  Open binary in hex editor Go to the 1st section (on example above to 0x1000) Section should start in this place, nulls should be before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Aslr</title>
      <link>/posts/disable-aslr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 14:00:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/disable-aslr/</guid>
      <description>Linux echo 0 | sudo tee /proc/sys/kernel/randomize_va_space radare2 # disable ASLR &amp;amp; reanalyse dor aslr=no aaa Windows Windows 7  Open RegEdit Goto: HKLM\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Session Manager\Memory Management\ Create new value (not a key): MoveImages with value 0. Reboot.  Windows 10 Disable ASLR per file Set-Processmitigation -Name name.exe -Disable ForceRelocateImages Disable ASLR by default  Search in Windows for: “windows defender Security Center” Click on the second icon from the bottom: “App &amp;amp; browser control” Scroll to the bottom and click on: “Exploit protection settings” Set “Force randomization for images “ to OFF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your Notes Organized (bear2mdtree demo)</title>
      <link>/posts/keep-your-md-notes-organized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/keep-your-md-notes-organized/</guid>
      <description>Journey of finding ideal note-taking app  TL;DR: If you want to transfer your bear notes to markdown goto Move your bear notes, if you want to emulate Bear multi-tagging check Multitagging support.
 Once upon a time I was using Bear.app for writing and organizing notes. It had really good features like multi-tagging and couple of other nice features like pseudo markdown support. Unfortunatelly a lot of things were bugged, developers slow in fixing them so I decided to move my notes from Bear to other platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; assembly</title>
      <link>/posts/c&#43;&#43;-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 14:50:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/c&#43;&#43;-assembly/</guid>
      <description>Structures C struct vs C++ class C struct  functions are loosely correlated with paramaters, parameters are usually passed via pointer, it may look like array for struct with 2 identical parameters in struct, for structures created dynamically look for malloc with non-usual size.  C++ class  Find constructor, it have always 1 argument (this pointer -&amp;gt; thiscall), main() function have initialization function __main with ctor initlizers, after creation of class with new operator the class constructor is called (can be empty), Methods are called with thiscall convention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi all!
I created this blog mostly for sharing some interesting stuff from topics of my interests, like:
 reversing (mostly Windows binaries), development, my repo script demos - how to use them.  Most of my notes are created in note-like style - not without the reason -&amp;gt; it can be mine note which I decided to share. Each series should have individual tag with additional helper tags for better searching.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>