<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trib0r3&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on trib0r3&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:06:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Aslr</title>
      <link>/posts/disable-aslr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:06:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/disable-aslr/</guid>
      <description>Linux echo 0 | sudo tee /proc/sys/kernel/randomize_va_space radare2 # disable ASLR &amp;amp; reanalyse dor aslr=no aaa Windows Windows 7  Open RegEdit Goto: HKLM\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Session Manager\Memory Management\ Create new value (not a key): MoveImages with value 0. Reboot.  Windows 10 Disable ASLR per file Set-Processmitigation -Name name.exe -Disable ForceRelocateImages Disable ASLR by default  Search in Windows for: “windows defender Security Center” Click on the second icon from the bottom: “App &amp;amp; browser control” Scroll to the bottom and click on: “Exploit protection settings” Set “Force randomization for images “ to OFF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; assembly</title>
      <link>/posts/c&#43;&#43;-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 14:50:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/c&#43;&#43;-assembly/</guid>
      <description>Structures C struct vs C++ class C struct  functions are loosely correlated with paramaters, parameters are usually passed via pointer, it may look like array for struct with 2 identical parameters in struct, for structures created dynamically look for malloc with non-usual size.  C++ class  Find constructor, it have always 1 argument (this pointer -&amp;gt; thiscall), main() function have initialization function __main with ctor initlizers, after creation of class with new operator the class constructor is called (can be empty), Methods are called with thiscall convention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi all!
I created this blog mostly for sharing some interesting stuff from topics of my interests, like:
 reversing (mostly Windows binaries), development, my repo script demos - how to use them.  Most of my notes are created in note-like style - not without the reason -&amp;gt; it can be mine note which I decided to share. Each series should have individual tag with additional helper tags for better searching.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>